Watch Online Movies and Series for FREE
www.osdb.link/lm
[man]
There's a legend of a man
who lives beneath the sea.
He is a fisher of men.
The last hope of all those
who have been left behind.
Many survivors claim to have
felt his gripping hands
beneath them.
pushing them up to the surface.
whispering strength
until help could arrive.
But this. of course.
is only a legend.
[man] Help!
- [woman yelling]
- [man] Over here!
- [both gasping]
- [man] Help!
Ma'am. I'm a Coast Guard rescue
swimmer. I'm here to help you.
- Sir.
- Here.
Stay with your flotation.
I'll be back for you.
- Don't leave me!
- Stay there.
[man] Don't you leave me!
[whimpering]
Basket is outside
the cabin door. going down.
- [pilot] Roger. Copy you.
- Boarder. right 30.
Boarder. right 15.
- [pilot] Right 15.
- Hold. hold. hold.
Basket is in the water.
Swimmer and survivor
have the basket.
Put your head in for me.
- [gasping]
- Help me.
[coughing] Take it up!
[man] Easy forward.
Let go!
- No.
- Let go!
- Let go. you're drowning her!
- [grunting]
Help me.
Help me. please. [grunts]
[woman whimpering]
Whoa! Swimmer just popped him
in the face.
OK. he's putting the man
in the basket.
Man is in the basket.
Taking the load.
[screaming]
Whoa. Big wave.
Get out! Get out! What's wrong
with you? Sit there and shut up.
[man] Swimmer in sight.
Prepare to take the load.
I have the
ready-for-pickup signal.
Swimmer is approaching
cabin door.
Survivor looks unconscious.
Swimmer inside of cabin door.
- [coughing. gagging]
- Cabin door closed.
- [continues coughing]
- [radio chatter]
[man retching]
God. I think you just
broke my nose.
And you may have killed
your wife. sir!
Twenty minutes
to Kodiak.
[man] Roger.
He's giving her CPR.
[pilot] Com-tech Kodiak.
this is Coast Guard 6096.
We have two hypothermic
survivors on board.
Be there in 20 minutes.
Requesting an ambulance
on scene when we land.
[gasping. crying]
[man chuckling] Whoa!
There we go.
- [man] Got her?
- We got her!
[laughing]
[radio chatter]
[continues laughing]
That a way. baby!
- [woman coughing]
- There's dead...
[exhales]
...and then there's dead.
[man] I swear
you get better with age.
[exhales]
[indistinct chatter]
[woman] Oh. we're not
going home.
- Had to hit him. huh?
- Yeah.
You are not...
Stay over there!
You stay over there
until you hear me!
Don't come near me.
Seems like it's always
the big ones that crack.
Lieutenant.
Crew said that she went under.
They thought you'd lost her.
Lucky guess.
Luck my ass.
[indistinct radio chatter]
I didn't think you were serious.
Of course you didn't. Ben.
How could you think I was
serious?
I'm not some nameless
drowning victim.
Oh. gee. I'm sorry saving lives
doesn't jibe with our social
cal...
[stammering] That's. um...
That's my chair.
He's right.
Not that chair.
I'm sorry. I was just pointing
things out in the living room.
They didn't know.
I would never take your chair.
Pick it up. What's...?
It doesn't have
to be messy. Ben.
It's clean. simple for both
of us. We don't have kids.
Well. what about Friday?
What about Friday?
We were gonna go with Carl
and Bridgette. you know.
to that...
...dinner dance thing
at the base.
[exhales] The base?
All you can eat wings?
A dart game to settle the tab?
That's the date we can't break?
- You're right. You're right.
- Wow.
Look. we'll... We'll go away.
all right? Just us.
It's too late. Ben.
I don't know what I can say to
you that I haven't said already.
It's time for me
to rescue myself.
[phone ringing]
Maybe. uh... Maybe I should
be the one to move out.
- [machine]
You've reached Helen...
- [Ben] And Ben.
Leave a message.
I don't even know where
anything is in this house.
It's much easier this way.
[man over machine]
Senior Chief.
please report to base. [beeps]
I can... I can fix this.
All right? I...
I can...
I can fix this. Just...
Tell me what to do.
- [beeping]
- [sighs]
[beeping continues]
Just let me go.
- No. No.
- Just let me go.
[beeping]
You should answer that.
[man on radio]
Ready rescue helo 6096.
Swimmer one. return to base.
- I don't want to lose her.
- Then change.
Man. how many times we had
this conversation. huh?
The only way
for you to save it
is to give this up
and fly a desk.
Exactly.
She just wants to live.
Hey. maybe we can get a hobby.
Both of us.
- Something like fishing.
- Fishing?
- Yeah.
- Guys like us don't fish. Carl.
It'll work out.
Always does.
Let me ask you something.
seriously.
Is it too soon
for me to ask her out?
- You better...
- I guess so.
[waves crashing]
[man on radio]
Mayday. mayday. mayday.
This is cargo vessel Sea Queen.
We're at 55 degrees.
12 minutes North.
167 degrees. 10 minutes West.
We're taking on water.
We're abandoning ship.
I repeat. we're abandoning ship.
You make sure you
and the four men...
[speaking foreign language]
Son. look at me.
Look at me.
You're gonna be OK. Got that?
We're gonna be OK. OK.
[beeping. electric whirring]
[howling. gusting winds]
[helicopter blades whirring]
[beeping]
- We have a tail rotor de-ice
caution light.
- Any secondary?
No. Circuit breakers are in
so it definitely has failed.
We're not building up any ice.
- How's the fuel?
- 40 minutes to bingo.
All right. take the stick.
- OK. I have the controls.
- All right. huddle time. boys.
We have a de-ice fail.
We're low on fuel.
The rulebook says
we cut our losses.
What do you think. Ben?
Well. if we go home...
they die. Bill.
[pilot] Kodiak.
this is Coast Guard 6096.
We have a tail rotor de-ice
caution light.
but we are pressing on.
[man] 609er 6. keep us updated
on your status.
- [pilot] 6096 status...
- Get the maintenance chief.
I wanna know
what he thinks about this.
[waves crashing]
[man grunting. yelling]
[man 1] Computer is saying
winds at 60-85 knots.
You're on your own
with altitude.
[man 2] Roger.
Mark. Mark. Right side.
Debris in water.
- Request to open cabin door.
- [man 1] Roger. Open door.
[man 2] Kodiak Ops.
6096. we're on scene.
We have heavy debris in the
water. Commencing cover search.
Mark in known position.
I'm going in.
They're dead. Ben.
Ben. they're dead.
We don't know that.
There's six PIW's all tied
together. No signs of life.
- I think we may be too late.
- Not our call.
They're on scene.
They'll make the assessment.
Requesting to get wet. sir.
I ain't sending you fishing
for bodies. Not in this.
Well. how about
fathers and sons?
Flare! Flare!
We got a live one here.
we got a live one.
You got five minutes.
Then we're hauling
your ass back up.
[man] Kodiak Ops.
this is Coast Guard 6096.
We have people in the water
and we are deploying
our swimmer.
[man] 609er 6. Kodiak Ops. copy.
[Carl] One's holding the flare.
I see no other movement.
- [pilot] Roger that.
- [Carl] Swimmer's ready.
- Check swimmer.
- Roger. Checking swimmer.
Swimmer's dress-down
checklist is complete.
Five minutes.
[Carl] Swimmer's away.
- Swimmer's OK. Clear back
and left 40.
- Clear back and left.
- How we looking on fuel. there?
- Two minutes to bingo.
I'm a Coast Guard rescue swimmer
here to help you. son.
You're gonna be OK. I'm gonna
get you in that helicopter.
- I have the
ready-for-pickup signal.
- Roger.
Basket is going out
of the cabin door.
Bingo. We're at bingo. Gotta go.
[Carl] Ease it back. Hold.
The basket is in the water.
We're out of time.
We gotta go. Carl.
[Carl] Hold position.
Steady. Hold.
He's putting the survivor
in the basket.
- [man] ...going crazy.
- Yeah. I know.
I'm all over the place.
Come on. Carl.
We gotta go. now!
[Carl] Don't have a
ready-for-pickup signal yet.
- Carl! Carl! Behind you!
- Holy shit!
We lost our tail rotor.
- [grunting]
- Mayday. Mayday. Mayday.
[screaming]
- We're going down.
- Mayday. Mayday.
[gasping]
- Carl.
- I'm here.
- Ben.
Hold on. Carl.
Hold on.
They'll be coming for us.
I've got you.
You're OK now.
- You're OK. I'm here. Carl.
- [gasping. coughing]
We're OK. Hang on.
I've got you.
[Carl] You think
they're coming?
[Ben] Oh. yeah.
They're coming.
I want a C-130
over that crash site now.
- Lieutenant Krauss.
start the mishap checklist.
- Aye. captain.
I've got an EPIRB hit
on Randall's survivor suit.
Launch ready helo.
swimmer provide.
We have a C-130 coming off
from KCAW at two.
- It's already low on fuel.
- I don't care. Cut an engine.
I want him to know
he's not alone out there.
Listen.
[airplane engine whirring]
You hear that?
Hold on. Carl.
Here we go. I've got you.
What's the ETA
on the backup helo?
En route to Cold Bay.
Should be on scene three.
maybe four hours.
Make it three.
- [sighs]
- [vomiting. coughing]
Jesus. how much more of that
stuff do you think I got in me?
- You feel that?
- [gasping]
- [groaning] Yeah.
It means you're alive.
I'm not gonna let go.
- Don't you!
- I'm not gonna.
I'm not gonna.
[shivering. groaning]
[helicopter blades whirring]
Serious fractures like in the
C-spinal should cause paralysis.
Mostly what we see is old
fractures in the arms.
also in the leg.
But nothing acute. nothing new.
[indistinct chatter]
We've been friends a long time.
haven't we? I've always been
good to you. haven't I?
Didn't promote you to a desk
when you turned 40
like everybody else.
- That's right.
- All right. so now I need you
to listen to me.
OK.
There's an instructor opening
at "A" School in...
- No. The answer is no.
- You just said you'd listen.
- Sit down.
- I'm not interested. captain.
Well. it's no longer a request.
Senior Chief. Sit down.
You're serious?
You have two choices.
Sign the papers today and you
can live life as a civilian
here in Kodiak
if that's what you want.
Or you can take that "A" School
opening I'm offering you.
- [scoffs]
- I've already spoken
to command down there.
It will be your class.
You will be in charge.
You can take the time to work
your way back into shape.
- I am in shape.
- Goddamn it.
That's not
what I'm talking about.
[exhales]
Ben. all I'm asking is that you
go down there for a few months.
You work with the kids.
you recharge. you...
...download that epic résumé
where it's gonna do some good.
You can't always be the one
in the water. Ben.
You'll know when you're
ready to come back.
- [marching cadence]
- [whistle blowing]
You people got 15 seconds
to get off this bus!
- [man 1]Move! Move. let's go!
- [man 2]Get off the bus!
[indistinct yelling]
[electronic whirring]
[man] Put your white books
in your red bags.
Let's get that squared away now.
Put those books away.
Put down your bags.
Fall out to the rear.
Follow two flights
and patter up the hall.
The rest of you. pick a bunk.
Put on your ODU's.
You started with 15 minutes.
You are now down to 12. Move!
Move. move. move. move!
- Short time. short time.
- One. two...
- Over here.
- [man] Hurry up. move it out.
- Top.
- All right.
[man] Find your rack.
Quit wasting my time.
Hey.
Hey. That's my stuff. man.
Hey. That's his bunk.
You two a couple?
It's OK...
I like the top better anyway.
[man] Out of the 39.000 men
and women who make up
the United States Coast Guard.
- There are only 280
rescue swimmers.
- Let's go! Let's go!
This is because we are
the Coast Guard's elite.
We are the best of the best.
When storms shut down
entire ports. we go out.
When hurricanes ground the
United States Navy. we go out.
And when the Holy Lord Himself
reaches down from heaven
and destroys His good work
with winds that rip houses
off the ground.
we go out.
And the attrition rate at this
school is well over 50 percent.
So if by some miracle you
actually have what it takes
to become one of us.
then. you get to live
a life of meager pay
with the distinct
possibility of dying
slow. cold and alone
somewhere in the vast sea.
However. you also get
the chance to save lives.
And there is no greater calling
in the world than that.
So. ladies and gentlemen.
welcome.
Welcome to "A" School.
Are there any questions?
Captain. Airman Fischer.
I just have one question.
That guy who holds all them
records... Is he still alive?
- Why do you ask?
- I just thought you ought
to let him know
- I'm about to knock
his name off that board.
- Really?
Why don't you let him know
yourself?
He's standing right behind you
in the back of the room.
Class. turn around and greet
Senior Chief Ben Randall.
Senior Chief Randall
will be your lead instructor
for the next 18 weeks.
Senior Chief Randall
is one of the most decorated
rescue swimmers
in the history of the
United States Coast Guard.
Ben. would you care
to address the class?
No. I think there's been
enough talk for one day.
Chief Skinner.
they're all yours.
- Attention on deck!
- Carry on.
Aye. captain.
PT test begins at 0700 tomorrow.
Class dismissed.
You will file through
the front door.
First row first.
followed by the second.
- Frank.
- [sighs]
- When God rips houses
off the ground?
- [chuckling]
I was rolling.
And I didn't mean to put you
on the spot up there.
[Skinner] Let's move. come on.
I was real sorry
to hear about your crew.
Come on. I'll show you around.
So I hear you're staying
in a single?
Yeah. Helen's got some
family business she's gotta
take care of up there.
[man] Mayday. mayday. mayday.
We are on fire!
[gasping]
[alarm beeping]
- [whistle blowing outside]
- [man] Let's go!
- Let's go. let's go. let's go.
- Get it. get it. get it.
Let's move it now!
Let's move it out!
Work as a team!
- [indistinct shouting]
- Hurry up!
- Two lines.
- Two lines. Let's go.
[chattering continues outside]
[man shouting]
Where's my class leader?
[sighs]
[man shouting]
Turn around! Turn around.
The only authorized command
to get you back up on your
feet is "pop tall."
[all] Yes. Petty Officer Hall.
- Do you understand me?
- [all] Yes. Petty Officer Hall.
Very well. Let's try it.
Lean and rest.
Pop tall!
[out of synch] Ooh-rah.
What the hell was that?
That was terrible!
Let's try that again.
Lean and rest! Together as one!
[groaning]
[grunting]
- Twenty-two.
- Down. Up.
- Twenty-three.
- Twenty-four.
- Get that ass down!
[all] Twenty-five.
That is absolutely horrible.
Pop tall. To the lone pine
and back.
Go! Move your ass!
Let's move it! Get it going!
[man] Let's go! Let's go!
- Bring 'em back.
- [man] Circle back.
- Let's go. Get back in line!
- Let's move!
Right back in PT formation.
PT formation.
Lean and rest.
Senior Chief on deck.
[straining]
[marching cadence indistinct]
[men chanting]
Don't need no land.
don't need no trees!
[all straining]
Mmm-hmm.
- [straining continues]
- Pop tall.
[all clapping] Ooh-rah!
I don't care who you are.
where you are from
or where you are going.
I care about one thing
and one thing only.
That is the future victims
you will be asked to save.
If I feel that you
will fail them.
I will fail you.
Understood?
[all] Yes. Senior Chief!
Hodge.
Where are you from. Hodge?
I'm from T-Neck. New Jersey.
Senior Chief.
Hodge is our triple repeat.
Do you plan on making it
this time. three-peat?
I really hope to. Senior Chief.
Yeah.
well hope don't float. Hodge.
You better start to learn
to swim against the current
and not with it.
Aye. aye. Senior Chief.
Fisch?
Fisch. why are you here. Fisch?
I'm here to exceed your
expectations. Senior Chief.
I'm a rescue swimmer at heart.
Born. bred. and water-fed.
Ooh-rah!
Wow. I'll bet you practiced
that all morning.
Mr. Fischer is our
high school swim champ.
He's had scholarships
to every Ivy League.
Oh. I'm sorry. I didn't realize
that he was so qualified.
I mean. you set records
in a pool?
That's amazing.
I'll bet it was like. what.
eight feet deep
in the deep end?
What if your nose plug
didn't work?
What if another swimmer
had cut into your lane.
[stifling laughter]
For the love of God.
you could have been killed.
Your schedule says that
you will perform a PT test
this morning.
That will not be necessary.
Water is where you've been
called to serve...
...water is where
you will be tested.
[whistle blowing]
This will serve in place
of your PT end test.
This is a go/no-go exercise.
You will tread water
for one hour.
You touch the wall. you fail.
You touch the bottom. you fail.
You fail. and you go home.
Senior. this school operates
on a two-challenge rule.
You can't throw them out
on their first day.
If you cannot survive in a warm
pool of water. then you have no
business being here.
Does this class understand?
- [all] Yes. Senior Chief!
- Ooh-rah. class 5506.
Now. who here can tell me
the rescue swimmer's motto?
So others may live.
Senior Chief.
Whoa. I feel safer already.
You willing to sacrifice
your life so others may live.
Goldfish?
Yes. I am. Senior Chief.
You will have to earn
that right.
I want all of you
to think about that.
There is going to come a time
when you reach
the point of exhaustion.
You'll want to give up.
The question is...
will you?
[Skinner] There are three
letters that will set you free.
D-O-R. Drop on request.
Look at that.
A waste of time.
[grunting]
- You all right?
- Stay up.
[gasping]
[man] Somebody help him up!
[indistinct shouting]
[overlapping shouts]
[man] Help him up.
- Help him out.
- Hold him up.
[overlapping shouts]
Lyons. relax. man.
[grunting. panting]
You're dismissed.
But. I cramped up.
You're gone.
[man] Let's go. Lyons.
out of the water.
Hurry up. let's go.
On your feet.
[Ben] First lesson
in physics. people.
Muscle does not float.
Petty officer Watson.
pull them out of the pool.
Aye. aye. Senior Chief.
Let's go. people.
out of the water.
[blows whistle] Hurry up!
Let's move people. hurry up!
[man] Class winner. right here.
I thought you said you
were willing to sacrifice
your life for another.
I am. Senior Chief.
Then why didn't you save
your teammate when he
reached out for you?
[panting]
I wasn't aware we were working
as a team. Senior Chief.
That's the only way we work.
swim champ.
Aye. aye. Senior Chief.
[♪ Ozomatli: Saturday Night]
♪ Get ready
for the Saturday night ♪
♪ Dip. dive. socialize
Get ready ♪
♪ Uh ♪
♪ Imagine waking up.
solidarity is evident ♪
- Asshole.
- Come again.
You heard me.
Hey. Hey. Hey.
Ease up. Ease up.
- What? Huh?
- It's not worth it.
Good news.
I think there's an opening
on my buoy tender.
I'll put in a word for you. huh?
I'm really gonna
miss that guy.
Hey. man.
what are you doing?
You got your bunk back.
♪ Hey. dip. dive ♪
- Captain.
- Ben. come in.
You work fast.
Lyons? He was one
of our top candidates.
Sometimes you gotta
shoot a hostage.
Look. we all know that
you're a legend. and all.
but our program
has been proven to work.
There's a gap between
training and what really
happens out there. Cujo.
- Oh really?
- That's right.
My intention is
to narrow that gap.
If someone has a problem
with that idea.
I'd like to hear about it.
Is this how it's gonna be. sir?
Yes. it is.
Permission to be dismissed. sir?
[Frank] Granted.
Let's go. let's go.
Keep it together. Look tight.
Keep it together.
Let's go. Let's move.
You have three minutes to get
this gear on. All of it.
[man] Set. go.
[♪ Kasabian: Club Foot]
Let's go!
Are you ready?
[whistle blows]
♪ One... take control of me ♪
Hello. I'm a rescue swimmer!
♪ Said it's two.
it's another trick ♪
Don't quit on me.
♪ Messing with my mind.
I wake up ♪
♪ Chase down an empty street ♪
♪ Blindly snap
the broken beats ♪
♪ Said it's gone
with the dirty trick ♪
♪ It's taken
all these days to find ya ♪
♪ Ah. ah. ah ♪
♪ I tell you I want you ♪
Do you hear me?
Pop tall! Pop tall! Pop tall!
[all yelling]
If you make a mistake.
just fess up to it.
take your licks.
and we'll press on.
Everybody now is going to pay
for your potty mouth.
- Down. Up... Down.
- [all] One!
- Up.
- [all] Three!
- Down. Up.
- [all] Five!
[chanting]
♪ Ah. ah. ah ♪
♪ I tell you I want you ♪
Are you crazy?
That's a command to get up!
- [all] Ooh-rah!
- Get down. Get down.
[cheering. yelling]
♪ Ah. ah. ah ♪
♪ I'll say that I want you ♪
♪ I'll say that I need you ♪
♪ Ah. ah. ah ♪
[grunting]
♪ Just wanted you near me ♪
- Ooh-rah!
- Ooh-r... [grunts]
[air horn blows]
♪ I say that I want you ♪
Ah. Can you die
from chlorine poisoning?
I can't feel my legs.
I'm serious.
Hoo... I don't know about
you guys. but I feel good.
This Randall guy. he's operating
on some whole other cylinder.
What is it. two weeks and he's
failed almost half the class?
- Mmm-hmm.
- He's a legend.
- They say he's got
something like 200 saves.
- I heard it was three.
Who cares what his number is.
If he's such a stud. what's he
doing here?
Whoo. How we feeling. boys?
Hey. Z. where you going?
My sister's best friend
is getting married
and they're having
a big reception downtown.
I promised her I'd go.
You said a wedding reception?
[yelling inside van]
[chattering]
All right. boys. let's go eat.
[woman] ♪ And if that
mockingbird don't sing ♪
♪ Daddy's gonna buy you
a diamond ring ♪
- Congratulations.
- Thanks.
[chattering]
[Ben] Yes. uh. Kodiak. Alaska.
The number for Helen Randall.
Um... OK. try Helen Freeman.
You betcha.
[phone ringing]
[answering machine]
Hi. You've reached Helen.
Leave a message.
Helen. it's Ben.
Jesus. that was weird.
You haven't had to use your
maiden name since we were kids.
Helen. if you're there.
just pick up. We need to talk.
Please.
[turns off phone]
[all laughing]
All right. All right.
To those who have fallen.
to those who have survived
phase one.
- Cheers.
[overlapping chatter]
And. and to our gal. Lindsey.
You can rescue me anytime.
- Oh. did he just say that?
- You did not just say that.
- You know what. Duran?
You. I think I might
actually let drown.
[all] Oh!
[woman]
♪ Don't you ever feel sad ♪
♪ Just lean on me
when the times are bad ♪
Hey. Senior Chief.
Good to see you.
Maggie is hot tonight.
♪ In a bit of trouble
and about to drown ♪
♪ Hold on. I'm comin' ♪
The place has not changed.
- From Kodiak. Alaska...
- Don't.
...Senior Chief Ben Randall
is in the house.
Big as day and still alive.
I must owe somebody money.
[laughing]
- You're terrible.
- Oh.
I heard a rumor you were gonna
be teaching here in town.
If that ain't the karmic wheel
spinning. I don't know what is.
[sighs] Well...
To the prodigal's return.
Where's your better half?
She decided to stay home.
- Oh. [laughing]
- Work stuff.
Yeah. Winter in Kodiak.
Let me see.
winter in Louisiana.
- Stop.
- And she decided to stay home.
Well. it's a good thing we got a
full bottle and half the night.
Yes. we do.
[lounge music playing]
Ooh. Check it out.
She's staring at you.
- That girl right there
is not staring at me.
- Did you just point at her?
- Did she see you point?
- I don't know.
[chuckling] All right. now you
gotta go talk to her. You gotta
go make a move.
- Yeah.
- I... I can't.
I just don't feel comfortable
right now. talking to women.
- You tell me you want to jump
out of helicopters for a living.
- You're talking to me.
- but you can't talk to a girl?
- That's exactly what
I was telling you.
All right. look.
I'm gonna help you out here.
I'll show you how it's done.
[clears throat]
Pick out the hottest girl
in here. I'll take her home.
- Oh. gosh. Here he goes now.
- No. how about
I will find the girl.
All right.
- Okeydoke.
- Who you thinking?
Make sure she's hot.
- Where are you looking?
- OK. At the bar. uh...
Two o'clock.
- Oh. Yes.
- That's a good one.
- That one?
- Yeah. that one.
A hundred bucks says she shuts
you down in less than a minute.
[chuckles] That looks
like a bet to me. Jake.
That's a bet.
All right.
All right. A hundred bucks says
I close in less than a minute.
Oh. Absolutely.
- A little liquor.
- Hats off. man.
- Tick-tock. tick-tock.
- The clock starts
when I talk to her.
- That's fine.
- This is gonna be embarrassing.
- All right. buddy.
- [man] What do you think?
- Think he's gonna do it?
- [man 2] No.
Evening. ma'am.
Can I buy you a drink?
I don't think so.
[whispering] You don't know
what you're missing.
[scoffs]
You sure you wanna go
with that one?
That's like your top
of the line. A-game material?
See. the way I see it.
you got two choices here.
Walk away from me.
or walk out of here
with me and split the cash.
Cash? [scoffs]
What cash?
The money you bet your friends
you could pick me up.
- See. that makes me nervous.
- She's shutting him down.
How much time you got left?
- About 20 seconds.
- Shall we?
- [Lindsey] Oh. my God.
- [Weatherly] No way.
[Hodge] It looks like they're
leaving the bar together.
No way.
You have got to be kidding me.
- Unbelievable.
- How'd he do that?
- I'm impressed.
There's a bar outside your base
called Maggie's. You know it?
- Yeah.
- Good.
Meet me there next Friday
around eight?
- You got a name?
- Yeah. Don't forget my money.
- [car starts]
- You got a middle name?
You do realize I can't
go back in there?
[alarm buzzing]
This is the sound
of death knocking.
SAR alarms and sleep
deprivation are part...
Where the hell are they?
[all shivering. shuddering]
The first stages of hypothermia
are the most dreadful... Why?
Because you still have
the ability to think. Say it.
[all] We still have
the ability to think.
The decisions you make
during this stage
are gonna determine
whether you live or die.
- [Ben] Is there a reason
you're not breathing. Goldfish?
- Huh?
Is there a reason
why you're not breathing?
I don't know anyone who can
stay alive without breathing
for 15 minutes. Senior Chief.
Are you a coroner?
Because pronouncing people
dead is not part of our job
description.
- What do we always say?
- [all] There's dead.
and then there's dead.
We never stop. Jake.
Not from the cabin
to the tarmac. We never stop.
- Aye. aye. Senior Chief.
- Understood?
- [all] Yes. Senior Chief.
- OK. Jake. In the pool.
- Hodge. you're up.
- You're with the dummy.
[gasping]
All right. now.
Three letters.
Three letters will get you
people a cup of hot coffee
and a blanket.
What do you say. Goldfish?
I'm actually not that cold
anymore. Senior Chief.
You're not cold anymore because
blood is moving from your...
outer extremities to your heart.
That's why your arms won't work.
You can plan on spending roughly
60 percent of your career
in a mildly hypothermic state.
Senior Chief. may I have a word?
Yes. sir?
Why wasn't I informed of this?
You know. we have classrooms.
Your assignment is to simply
teach the stages of hypothermia.
[shivering] Sir... In about
two and a half... minutes.
they'll understand.
Permission to carry on. sir?
Go ahead.
[grunting]
[all groaning]
[shivering] Three letters.
people. will get you a...
...hot cup of coffee
and a warm blanket.
[chuckling]
What do you say. class 5506?
[all weakly] Ooh-rah.
[Ben] This is an oxygen
deprivation. anaerobic exercise.
You and your partner
will push your brick
along the bottom of the pool.
down and back.
If you need air.
you may surface. One breath.
Your partner must remain
underwater until you return.
Your brick can only move while
both of you are touching it.
If you both surface.
you both fail.
This exercise is designed
to teach you teamwork.
On my whistle. drop your gear
into the pool and pair up.
[gasping. panting]
I said one breath. Sunkist.
let's go.
- I can't... I can't.
- Come on.
I can't. Get your ass
out of the pool. let's go.
Come on! Lean and rest.
You wanna quit. just quit now.
I could use those new shoes.
Senior Chief.
we've got a problem.
Somebody's missing.
Jesus Christ.
That's gotta be
a new record. Ooh-rah.
I'm so sick of records.
Go get him.
[gasping. panting]
You think I'm impressed
because you can hold
your breath. Goldfish?
I wouldn't venture to say what
would impress you. Senior Chief.
All right. Get him out of the
pool. We're done for the day.
Out of the pool. Fischer.
let's move.
- Ooh-rah!
- Move your ass.
- Pop tall. Sunkist.
- [Lewis] Out of the pool.
I want you right here. class
leaders. The rest of you dress
down. Right here. let's go.
Records.
Never stare directly
into the flame. people.
It will impair
your night vision.
This is a Mark 58 flare.
This is what it looks like.
It will light up
a 50 foot swath of water.
and can be detected
by infrared miles out.
This is a demonstration model.
The normal one will burn
for 40 to 60 minutes.
[Hall] Hey. pay attention.
The Mark 58 is used to reference
the wind. to detect the current.
Officer Watson is gonna talk
a little bit more about that.
Five minutes.
The vessel. you're looking at
right now. people. is listing
to the port side.
As a rescue swimmer. when you
get the door of the helicopter.
you need to look down
and pay attention to what you
really have down there.
It's very important that you
understand your limitations.
Limitations without
understanding are gonna
get you killed.
Case in point. this vessel's
trapped in pancake ice
in the Bering Sea.
As you can see the crew out on
the deck in a relatively
manageable hoisting position.
But suddenly...
Those pieces of ice can weigh in
upwards of thousands of pounds.
Now imagine yourself trapped
between two thousand pound
pieces of ice.
- trying to free swim.
- Thank you. Chief.
Next scenario.
Petty Officer Watson.
[Watson] Before you leave that
helicopter. going down...
Standardization is one of the
reasons we were so successful
during Katrina.
We had crews come in
from all over the country.
But it didn't matter.
because we have all been
trained the same way.
I didn't know my pilot.
I didn't know my co-pilot
or my flight mechanic.
But guess what.
It didn't matter. because...
That's why we do it.
So you have to get your mind
wrapped around that idea.
When that helicopter starts
going. When the wind starts
coming. When...
- Down. up.
- [all] Twenty!
- [all] Twenty-one!
- Down. up.
- [all] Twenty-two!
- [all] Twenty-three!
- Two... Three.
- Down. Up.
[chanting] Don't need no land.
Don't need no trees
Out in the water
there's work for me.
[♪ SheDaisy:
Something To Talk About]
♪ We stand
just a little too close ♪
♪ We stare
just a little too long ♪
- Hey. Mags. can I have a beer?
- Sure.
Well. well. So you are
gonna have a drink with me.
No. I'm having a drink near you.
Entirely different thing.
Pretty little lightning rod.
aren't you?
- What's your name?
- Daisy Buchanan.
You're lying.
Daisy Buchanan.
There is that possibility.
That was a surefire lie.
So I take it you've
read The Great Gatsby?
- Where's my money?
- It's not on me.
But it is close.
in a very safe place.
Now. I've drawn a map.
with a complex set of clues.
Each one is more fiendishly
clever than the last.
That works too.
This is just a picture
of your pants.
Yeah. but it's a bad picture.
which is what makes it
so fiendishly clever.
[laughing]
How did Emily Thomas
become a school teacher?
How does Jake Fischer
become a guy who wants
to jump out of helicopters?
I killed a couple guys
and had to get out of Dodge.
[laughs] You're lying.
There's that possibility.
[laughs]
The truth.
My bullriding career
was going down the drain.
OK. that's better.
All right. now you.
- I really should go.
- Go?
What? No. you're not going.
We're starting to have fun.
You're insulting my drawing.
No. you were
insulting your drawing.
Although. to be fair.
it's a pretty lame drawing.
Well. you can't go
'cause you owe me a dance.
No. I don't think so.
I'm gonna have to
take that money back.
I wouldn't feel right...
Every 18 weeks a new bunch
of you guys comes in
looking to score
with the local talent.
I live here.
I work here.
It's a good thing I'm just
asking for a dance. then.
♪ [Al Green: Love and Happiness]
OK. one dance.
No attachments.
Just casual.
I'm a guy.
I can do casual.
Mmm-hmm.
- I am the king of casual.
- Mmm.
There's just one thing. though.
You're gonna have to stop
undressing me with your eyes.
'Cause there's no way
you're getting me into bed.
♪ Talkin' about
how she can make it right ♪
♪ Oh. love and happiness ♪
♪ Love and happiness ♪
♪ I'm talkin' about love ♪
♪ Well. happiness is when ♪
♪ You really feel good
with somebody ♪
♪ There ain't nothin' wrong ♪
♪ With being in love
with someone ♪
- Hey you.
- [chuckles]
I gotta get to work.
I'm late.
- Wh... What is it?
- They're gonna kill me.
This isn't like school.
They don't hand out tardies
in the military.
- You smell really good.
- I smell like you.
- He never came back?
- Nope.
Wow. Four years as lead
instructor. I never had
one go missing.
All right. take the others
to the pool. I'll catch up.
Aye. aye. Senior.
[marching cadence]
Oh. God. there they are.
Stop the car. Stop.
- Here?
- Yes.
- I'll call you.
- You better. Bye.
[marching cadence continues]
[Emily] Jake! Jake! Jake!
[Skinner] Airman Fischer's
coming in late. yeah!
[all] Airman Fischer's
coming in late. yeah.
- Oh. ah. oh. ah. ay!
- Hi.
[all] Oh. ah. oh. ah. ay!
[Skinner] Must be nice
to go out on a date. yeah!
[all] Must be nice
Oh. my goodness.
Look at this.
Look at this. "Freshman
leads team to state title."
That's you.
Holy smokes.
"At only 16. Jake Fischer
displays the traits
of a seasoned athlete.
One thing's for sure.
the future looks bright
for this young competitor."
Hmm. Guess they didn't know
you were gonna flunk out
of "A" School.
[locker door slams]
You have a nice evening?
Get dressed.
[muffled grunting]
[panting. grunting]
I think we need another brick.
Bring it in.
Goldfish.
[all groaning]
Thanks to Mr. Fischer's
extracurricular activities.
you have all now gone
36 hours without sleep.
Blow it.
Class leader. you are done.
Form it up in the shallow end.
Aye. aye. Senior Chief.
Class 5506. form it up!
[chuckling] No...
No. no. no. no. no.
You're with me.
[chanting] I'm a rescue swimmer.
yes I am!
I'm here to pull your ass
out of this jam!
- I drop from the helo
and swing from the cable!
- All right. knock it off.
I am having a hard time
figuring you out. Fischer.
You mean you like seeing
your picture in the paper?
In it for the glory.
maybe a few chicks. am I right?
But when it comes down to it.
you will choose yourself
over them every time.
Like you did on the first day
in the pool.
Like you did yesterday.
on missing muster.
It won't happen again.
Senior Chief!
Why don't you do us both
a big favor and quit?
[chanting] I'm a rescue swimmer.
yes I am!
I'm here to pull your ass
out of this jam!
I drop from the helo
and swing from the cable!
I'm not Tarzan.
I'm just willing and able!
[panting] Give me something
else. Senior Chief!
- [chief] One. two. three.
- [all] Thirty-one.
- [all] Thirty-two.
- [chief] One. two. three.
- [all] Thirty-three.
- [all] Thirty-four.
- [chief] One. two. three.
- [all] Thirty-five.
- [all] Thirty-six.
- [chief] One. two...
- [Skinner] Stop. Drop 'em.
Senior Chief's on deck.
Pop tall.
[all] Ooh-rah!
[Ben whistling]
[Ben] Good morning. class.
Today we were going
to learn about how to
approach a drowning victim
in high seas.
But I think there's some here
who aren't interested
in that victim.
In fact. I think there's
some in this class
who aren't interested
in saving lives at all.
I believe there are some
who are more interested
in setting records.
So today is record day.
[♪ Black Rebel Motorcycle Club:
Ain't No Easy Way Out]
♪ Ain't no easy way ♪
♪ No there ain't
no easy way out ♪
[chuckling]
5:28.
Put one on the board
for Goldfish.
Wow. He's fast.
He's good.
♪ Ain't no easy way ♪
♪ No there ain't
no easy way out ♪
You got it. man!
You got it. Fisch!
- Another record. Chalk it up!
- Whoo!
- Get some!
- [Ben] You are the man!
[Ben] You people do not deserve
to be in the same pool as Jake.
He's destroying you!
Wow. Look at him go. He's fast.
Wow. He's fast.
Come on. You're all fighting
for seconds. Just first loser.
This is fun.
We'll pass out trophies later.
Unbelievable.
♪ Ain't no easy way ♪
♪ No there ain't
no easy way out ♪
Unbelievable.
♪ No there ain't
no easy way out ♪
Want me to pull
these pansies out?
♪ Ain't no easy way
No there ain't
no easy way out ♪
You do not want to hear
about my day.
Yeah. I do.
[groans]
Man. this guy. Randall...
You know. it doesn't matter what
I do. It's just not good enough.
Well. maybe he's just trying
to push you to be better.
You know. we teachers do that
to the ones we believe in.
No. It's personal with me.
He knows that I'm
better than he was.
I mean. today I broke
every one of his records.
I mean. it's like.
I own them all.
Not all of them.
There's one record
you won't break.
The Aegis.
Medical ship. caught on fire.
It was a nightmare. People were
burning in their beds.
And Ben Randall got every one
of those people off there.
except for this one guy...
And right when the ship started
to go down. he reaches down
and grabs this guy...
He's hanging from the cable
with this man's life in his
hands. and the winch jams.
It's 20 minutes to the base.
The man's screaming...
Ben looks him dead in the eye
and you know what he said?
- He said "I won't let go."
- [Emily] What happened?
Dislocated his shoulder.
tore every tendon in his hand.
But. he didn't let go.
Twenty minutes.
Just fingertips.
You break that record.
then you give me a call.
My day was all right.
[♪ Abby Ahmad: Tri-Me]
♪ I need to step outside ♪
♪ Another day
marks another way marks ♪
♪ A new reason to hide ♪
♪ It's true when you slip
you slide ♪
♪ On the ground
I've been pushed down ♪
♪ By this primitive pride ♪
♪ My voice a stifled symphony ♪
♪ My veins pump
liquid lethargy ♪
♪ But I may be turning blue ♪
♪ And I may have
some work to do ♪
♪ But try me ♪
♪ Tri-me ♪
[soft music playing]
So here's my thinking:
We should go on a date.
[chuckles]
What do you call this?
No. no. no. I'm talking
about like a real date.
You know. with like
a nice restaurant.
Some nice clothes.
I'll get you some flowers.
I thought we agreed
to keep this casual.
[stammering] Just one steak.
What is...?
One steak is not gonna forge
some kind of a lasting
emotional bond.
I'm serious.
- Yeah? So am I.
- Yeah.
It's one dinner.
What's it gonna hurt?
If you ordered a steak. I'd
imagine a cow would be involved.
What. do you have an art gallery
over here? What is this 2?
Ah... It's so the guy behind me
knows what place he's coming in.
[laughs]
What about this one?
That... [grunts]
...is the initials of the guys
on my high school relay team.
A drunken celebration
gone wrong?
[mock laughing]
Something like that.
- So. about this date...
- Oh. God. Just dinner. right?
No flowers.
Where we will discuss nothing
emotional or important.
[sighs] I am fully prepared
to do an entire hour on nothing
but the Chicago Bears.
And we can have completely
meaningless sex immediately
afterwards.
[gasps]
You think I'm gonna sleep
with you on our first date?
[scoffs] Think again.
- [laughing]
- You just head-butted me.
- [Jake] I'm gonna teach you
the breast stroke.
- [Emily laughs]
- It's very complicated.
- [Emily moans]
- Different than the butterfly.
- [chuckling]
[exhales] I guess...
I can't sleep.
Well. of course you can't.
Your wife left you.
Your best friend died.
You sound like
a damn country song.
- [grunts]
- If you had a dog.
it'd be run over by now.
So did she send you papers?
- Yeah.
- Did you read 'em?
No. I did not.
Well. you think
you might ought to?
You know. there never
was anyone else. Mags.
Like hell. Ben.
You're a bigamist.
You've been married
to the Coast Guard all along.
Give me that shoulder.
- [groans]
- You probably swum it
out of socket.
trying to prove
you was still 19. Am I right?
When the heck did we get old?
Hell. I've always been old. Ben.
You know what. though?
I don't mind.
I mean. if my muscles ache
it's because I've used them.
It's hard for me to walk up
them steps now.
It's 'cause I walked up 'em
every night
to lay next to a man
who loved me.
I got a few wrinkles
here and there.
but I've laid under thousands
of skies with sunny days. Yeah.
I look and feel this way.
well. 'cause I drank and I
smoked. I lived and I loved
and danced. sang.
sweat and screwed my way through
[chuckling]
a pretty damn good life.
if you ask me.
Getting old ain't bad. man.
Gettin' old. that's earned.
[gasps]
[exhales]
There will come a time
when you might have to decide
who lives and dies out there.
It's a terrible responsibility.
but it is one you will have to
make as a rescue swimmer.
The bigger reality is...
It's also something
you're going to have to
live with as a human being.
There will come a time when you
are going to have to say "no."
The most important person
to keep alive is yourself.
You'll be facing crews
from five to 20.
all saying. "save me. save me."
They're looking for a miracle.
- How old are you. Hodge?
- Twenty-four.
At twenty-four years old. you
have to become that miracle.
You have to find a way
to be that miracle.
Looking right.
Looking center.
Looking left.
Ooh-rah!
It's OK. sir.
- I'm a rescue swimmer. I'm...
- [grunts]
- [gasping]
- Again!
[muffled grunting]
[gasping. panting]
All right. that's it.
Time out.
Panics every time. Senior.
Hodge. over here.
Hey.
The only difference
between you and the victim
is the attitude in which
you enter the water.
You've gotta figure out a way
to be calm in the face of chaos.
Do you understand?
That's your first challenge.
Charlie.
One more. and you're gone.
- Come out.
- Aye. aye. Senior Chief.
- What's up?
- Hey. Fisch.
You don't have to take
his shit. Hodge.
What do you know?
It's so easy for you. Fischer.
Is that right?
[Hodge] Yeah.
No. you don't get it.
You don't realize
that you're tougher
than I am.
And how's that?
Well. if I get kicked out
of here. I'm not coming back.
I'm definitely not
coming back twice.
- I mean. you got guts. man.
- Stupidity.
How long you
been here. man?
All together. uh. I don't know.
Ten weeks first time.
six weeks. two days
second time.
Six weeks this time.
So you've been here longer
than anybody that's graduated.
But you don't think
you can make it.
Lighten up on yourself. man.
Let's go.
Let's get a beer.
Hey. wait. don't you have a date
with your girl from the wedding?
Yeah. but it's not till nine.
We got time. Get dressed.
- Let's go.
- [exhales]
[♪ Stevie "Funkworm" Butler:
Shake Up The World]
Wait. wait.
Where are we going?
Uh. Jake. that's a squid bar.
There's Navy guys everywhere.
I don't give a shit.
A beer's a beer.
When pulling through the water.
you'll pull yourself through.
- [Hodge] Uh-huh. I'll go fast.
- You wanna pull it.
♪ With a bulletproof screen
on the hood of my truck ♪
Hey. Charlie. you get those
finished reports before you
came off to get tanked up?
- Yes. sir. captain.
- I'll believe that
when I see it.
We go to "A" School.
which is the most difficult
school in the military.
The attrition rate's like...
what is it. fifty percent?
- Fifty percent.
- It's over fifty percent.
We're still here 'cause
we're the best of the best.
When storms shut down entire
ports. you know who goes out?
Uh. we do. When hurricanes
ground the US Navy.
these little guys over here.
guess who goes out.
That's right. we do.
Look. honey. you better
keep it down in here. OK?
OK. honey. She called me honey.
OK. honey. But when God Himself
reaches down from heaven...
- What does he do. Jake?
- Rips houses off
the foundation.
When God Himself rips houses
off the foundation. we go out.
'Cause we are rescue swimmers
and that is our job.
and that's what we do.
You might want to
recheck your compass.
This ain't no puddle pirate bar.
Um. no problem. Because. uh.
we were just leaving anyway.
Sit down. Hodge. Drink.
Finish your beer. Drink.
- Yeah. sit. Hodge.
- That's my beer. man.
Finished now?
Must be happy hour.
[grunts]
[yelling]
[laughing]
- Back off.
- [grunts]
Everyone in this place
is retired Navy.
Hey. Hey. when do I
get that phone call?
I know I get a phone call.
When do I get my phone call?
[piano music playing]
Ma'am. I'm sorry. but
if nobody comes in 20 minutes.
I need the table.
- OK. Yeah.
- I'm sorry.
She's never gonna
talk to me again.
You know they'll
kick us out for this. right?
Yep.
At least they can't say we quit.
I was never gonna make it.
anyway. Skinner's right.
I panic every time.
Screw Skinner.
- I'm Skinner. Break my hold.
- Hey. what are you doing. man?
- Come on. Fischer. get off me.
- Clock's ticking. Break it.
Fischer. you're hurting me. man.
Fischer. get off me. man.
Come on. Fischer.
you're hurting me.
Fischer. man. get off.
- Break the goddamn hold.
- Fischer. get off me!
- Break the goddamn hold. Hodge.
- [grunts]
- I said get off me!
All right. Now it's just like
that when you're in the water.
Well. now.
we can come back.
Give you boys time for a smoke
and some pillow talk.
[guards laughing]
[Fischer] Can't kick us out.
[Skinner] It's called
disorderly conduct. Yes. we can.
- We didn't fail at nothing.
- Our profession
is about control.
You both failed miserably
in that department.
Hold it right there.
- [Skinner knocking] Senior?
- Yeah.
Their disenrollment records.
- Bar fight?
- Mmm-hmm.
- All right. bring 'em in.
- Senior. Square it!
It's all my fault. Senior Chief.
Hodge had nothing to do with it.
- Is that true. Hodge?
- It's true.
All right.
Fine. you're dismissed.
- Senior Chief. I was...
- I said that you are dismissed.
Let's go.
You're gonna kick me out
for defending the Coast Guard?
The Coast Guard's been
around for 200 years.
I doubt a couple of knuckleheads
like yourself are gonna
defend it.
Sit down.
I've been trying to peel
the layers back on you
for a while now and I...
...I just don't get it.
I mean. this kind of work seems
a little remedial for someone
like yourself. you know.
Big swim champ. offer to every
Ivy League. you give it all up
to be here with us.
Why?
I'm here to save lives.
Senior Chief.
[exhales]
I spoke with
your coach. Jake.
- You spoke with my coach?
- Yeah. I spoke with your coach.
Something in your file just
kept... kept hanging me up.
You. uh. win the state
championship your freshman
and sophomore year.
then you don't swim
the next two.
I'm just a public school guy.
so. uh...
Pardon me. but it didn't add up
until... now.
"Kirk Holloway.
100 meter medley winner.
thrown through
the passenger window.
Pronounced dead at the scene.
Abe Ikeman.
first team All-American.
Lungs crushed.
Carl Sandoval.
50 meter freestyle champ. made
it all the way to the hospital.
Died of internal bleeding."
I guess you just know
everything. then.
I know what it's like
to lose a team.
Yeah?
What about living in a small
town where everyone thinks
you killed their brother.
or their son. or their best
friend? You know about that?
The kind of small town
where everyone still waves
to everyone...
just not to you?
I read the report. Jake.
Your blood alcohol was zip.
that night.
I'm guessing there was a flip
for designated driver. You lost.
I guess that just
makes it all go away. huh?
No. it doesn't
make it all right.
It just makes it an accident.
At least that's how it reads.
You were 16 years old. Jake.
I'm not your priest.
but if I was. I think...
...I think maybe
you deserve a pass.
You're giving me a pass?
You... You just think
you know everything.
With your psychobabble
bullshit.
- Why am I here?
- Why are you here? Huh?
You're too old to be doing this.
You washed up here.
You don't want to be teaching
a bunch of kids at a pool.
Am I right?
I don't give a shit what you
read. or who you talked to.
You don't know about me.
You don't...
I have me under control.
I can see that.
The only difference
between you and me is...
...I don't wear the ones
I lost on my arm. Jake.
I know where you're at. Jake.
I'm there myself.
I ask myself every day
why I was the one that survived.
- And?
- And...
And if I can't
answer that for me.
I'm certainly not going to try
and answer it for you.
Have a seat.
I want you to start being
a member of this team.
The team you have now.
You have a gift. Jake.
You're the best swimmer
to come through this program.
Hands down. by far.
You've got a whole
record board to prove it.
But you know what I see
when I look at it?
I see someone fast enough
who's gonna get there first.
I see someone strong enough
who's gonna last.
I see someone...
...who can save a life
that maybe nobody else could.
You really want to honor
the initials on your arm?
Then honor your gift.
Save the ones you can. Jake.
The rest... we've gotta let go.
Does this mean you're
not gonna fail me?
For what?
Backing up a buddy in a bar?
Man. I got bigger problems
than you.
I don't know about you.
but I could use a fucking drink.
Oops.
We're gonna consider everything
tonight off record and off duty.
- That was an invite.
- Oh.
You gotta be kidding me.
What was it they called you?
Puddle pirates.
But it's not... I'm...
I'm way over it.
Senior Chief. This is...
That's like sticks and stones.
Well. we'll just have one beer.
[country music playing]
Great.
They're angrier and drunker.
- Perfect.
- Hi. Two beers.
- You gotta be kidding me.
- That's what I said.
Look. I don't want
any trouble. OK?
They really don't like us.
do they?
No. They think they're
better than us because
they're combat-oriented.
We're the Coast Guard. Jake.
Nobody really appreciates us
until they need us.
Is that him?
Yep.
Hey. let me ask you a question
before we start bleeding.
All those saves...
What's your real number?
Do you have a death wish
or are you just shit stupid?
I'm gonna go with stupid
this time.
- Hi.
Who's this. your old man?
[chuckling]
You know. I'm really glad
you're still here.
- Oh yeah?
- Yeah.
[grunting]
- Behind you.
- [Navy chief] Stand down!
I said stand down!
I think you'd better leave.
OK.
Come on. Jake.
[country music continues]
All right. sit down.
Have a beer.
- That went a lot better
than I thought.
- Yeah.
- What the hell was that?
- I don't know.
Hey. uh.
I want to. uh. apologize to you.
About what I said earlier.
about you being old
and washed up and that.
Is there...?
Is there anything
you'd like to say to me?
Like what?
I don't know.
I apologized to you.
I just thought that...
You know. there might be
something you've said or done
that you'd like
to apologize to me for.
Why?
'Cause that's how
it's done. I...
You suck at apologies.
You know that?
I mean. you're missing
the whole concept.
[phone ringing]
- Hello?
- [Jake] Hi. It's me.
[exhales]
Are you OK? What happened?
I mean. I waited for two hours.
Yeah... No. I'm...
I'm really sorry. I...
- What happened?
- Um. it's a really long story.
Let me just... [sighs]
Let me put it this way.
It was the...
...best worst night of my life.
Well. I'm glad someone had fun.
Can I... see you tomorrow night?
I have parent-teacher
conferences tomorrow.
What about the next night?
I have parent-teacher
conferences all week.
- You blowing me off?
- No. Jake.
I wouldn't do that to somebody.
I gotta get up
in a couple hours. I gotta go.
Yep.
Goodbye. [dial tone]
[Ben] All right. You know
what we preached on the ground.
Same thing.
We're gonna stay together.
No matter what happens out
there. you stay together.
Whatever decision you make.
you make as a team.
We train to freefall
at 15 to 20 feet.
You fall from 50 feet.
that's like hitting concrete.
You fall 80 to 100 feet...
You die.
Hey. where are they going?
They're supposed to come back
for us. right?
I don't know.
Hodge. you've been here before.
They're gonna come back. right?
But I never made it this far.
- You're kidding?
- Not to the final week.
They're not coming back.
- What do we do?
- All right. Listen up.
We stay together as a group.
Nobody falls behind.
We all stay together.
One guy goes back.
we get him back up to the front.
OK? We're a team.
- Ooh-rah!
[Jake] Let's do it. 5506.
Sir. it's OK. I'm with
the US Coast Guard.
[grunting]
[Skinner] Again!
[grunts]
I'm a Coast Guard rescue
swimmer. I'm here to help you.
[blows whistle] Time out.
Class. pop tall.
Hodge. get yourself
to the side of the pool.
Aye. aye. Senior Chief.
[all] Ooh-rah!
Easy. Chief.
Guess that was
a lucky punch.
Hodge!
- You all right. Chief?
- You stay right there.
Well done. Charlie.
Well done.
Ooh-rah. Chief Skinner.
Class 5506. ooh-rah. Hodge.
On three...
- One. two. three!
- [all] Ooh-rah. Hodge!
Good for you.
- Get their gear off.
- [all yelling]
Get it off! Move!
I can't believe...
[all yelling]
[overlapping shouts]
- Get it off!
- Yeah.
Class 5506. will you come
find me if I am lost?
[all] Yes. Senior Chief!
Will you come save me
if I am drowning?
[all] Yes. Senior Chief!
I believe you would.
I have high hopes
for this class.
I have high hopes for you.
Matthew Stokes.
Savannah. Georgia.
- Matthew. job well done.
- Ooh-rah. captain.
Kenneth Weatherly.
Clearwater. Florida.
Go out there
and do great things.
William Hodge.
Astoria. Oregon.
- Where's Senior Chief?
- He had a chance to go back
to Kodiak. and he took it.
He never had much of a bedside
manner. He's a water dog. Jake.
As it turns out.
not a half bad teacher.
Best of luck.
Jacob Fischer.
Kodiak. Alaska.
- Congratulations. Jake.
Make us proud up there.
- Aye. aye. captain.
Scott Reeves.
Sitka. Alaska.
Ladies and gentlemen.
your graduates.
- [man] Ooh-rah.
- [applause]
- Congratulations.
- Thanks a lot.
- Good job. Weatherly.
- Good job.
- Sorry.
- [laughs]
- Well. congratulations.
- Thank you.
- I...
- It's OK.
We both knew where
this was going. right?
Just casual.
Right.
You're getting what
you've always wanted.
And always wanting more.
Take care of yourself. Jake.
[sighs]
- I gotta go to work.
- Yeah.
[sighs]
[seagulls squawking]
[man] Ladies and gentlemen.
welcome to the rock.
I'm Captain William Hadley.
C.O. of Kodiak air station.
- Fischer.
- Yeah. right here.
- Mr. Michetry will
square you away.
- Welcome.
The rest of you step up here
with Mr. Christiansen.
He will process you in.
Oh. amazing.
Not only does he come back
in great shape. but he
still thinks he can cook.
- Hello. Jake. Welcome.
- How you doing?
- Good to see you again.
- You guys keep it
warm here. huh?
Glad to know you know
where a free meal is.
And the stand team
arrives here next Tuesday.
Patch things up with the wife?
You fix things up
with that young lady?
Well. you still have
a choice. you know.
Hey. there was a question
I wanted to ask you
back in school.
And I didn't. But. um...
When you can't save 'em all...
...how do you choose who lives?
It's probably different
for everybody. Jake.
Kind of simple for me.
though. I just...
I take the first one
I come to.
Or the weakest one
in the group and I swim as fast.
and as hard as I can.
for as long as I can.
And the sea takes the rest.
Think I'm ready?
I'm not your teacher anymore.
Jake. I'm just your fellow
swimmer.
That's not exactly the answer
I'm looking for. there.
If I did not think you were
ready. I would not put you
in the Bering Sea.
[woman on radio] 6030.
this is Kodiak Ops.
We are diverting your
training mission.
We've two young kayakers swept
into the cave one mile south
of Saltery Cove. How copy?
[co-pilot] 6030 copies.
We're diverting at this time.
[pilot] We've got
a real case now. OK. guys.
High tides coming in and we've
got six to eight foot rollers
coming from the north.
Senior. what do you think
about taking Fischer with you?
I want him with me.
All right. he's good to go.
I don't think it's gonna be
a problem sliding in there.
I think the problem's gonna be
coming back out.
That's why I got Jake with me.
Got my human speedboat.
[pilot] Kodiak Ops.
this is 6030.
We're on scene at this time.
No sign of kayakers.
I'm taking her down.
Cabin door is open and locked.
[pilot] Those are definitely
ten foot waves.
Swimmer is coming
through the door.
Remember. all right.
You've got the whole flank
of the ocean.
Punch her through that opening.
You gotta read the hydraulics.
you gotta count the waves.
Then wait for the flush.
[man] Checking swimmer.
Sure as hell hope you paid
attention in class. Speedboat.
Swimmers in the water.
swimmers OK.
Swimmer two is making contact
with swimmer one.
- Hey! Over here.
- Here.
- Over here.
- Shout out. Three o'clock.
[man] We're right here.
We're rescue swimmers.
We're gonna get you out of here.
I can't believe you guys
actually got here.
Give me your hand.
- Just the two of you?
- Yeah. His arm's hurt real bad.
All right.
Swimmer one. I got. uh.
two survivors.
It's gonna be
a basket pick up here.
- [pilot] Roger.
- Broken here?
You take him first.
Get him in the basket.
I'll follow with the other one
right behind you.
- You got that?
- Yeah.
- You got it?
- Yeah. yeah.
All right. I'm gonna lower you
down in here. all right?
Relax. buddy. I got you.
- All right. You're with me.
- OK.
[groaning]
I don't swim so good.
- You don't swim so good?
- No. sir.
That's OK.
I swim pretty good.
All right. on your back.
- Wait. Aren't we
gonna take the boat?
- I'm the boat.
Wait. wait. wait.
I'm afraid. I'm not ready.
- Hey!
- Wait. I can't go
without the boat.
Settle down!
[man] Something's not right.
Swimmer one's going back
to the cave.
What happened?
He hit a log.
What? What do you...?
[grunting]
[groaning]
- He's gone. Jake.
- He's not!
[coughing]
He's just got a head laceration!
- Here we go.
- [groaning]
Let's go.
Let's go!
Senior Chief. Randall.
Lock it in.
Simple physics. We're just gonna
time the flush. all right?
All right...
You call it. swimmer. [spits]
[Jake] Now!
Hey. I know you're tired. OK?
I know you feel tired right now.
I need you to keep your eyes
open. OK? All right? All right?
Hey. I need you to keep talking
to him. Keep talking to him.
Senior. Senior!
Can you open these up for me?
One by one I want you
to hand them to me.
Reyes. he's fine.
- Right here. buddy.
Right here. OK?
- [man] OK.
[woman crying] Robert!
- I'm OK.
- He's got a compound fracture
of his right radius.
We tried to stabilize
that a little bit.
We put a collar on this one.
but it was more precautionary
than anything.
- Thank you.
- This one's possibly
concussive.
We've been checking their vitals
the whole way back.
Their both mildly hypothermic
but I think they'll come around.
- Bye.
- Thank you so much.
You're welcome.
It happens. Ben.
Not to me.
Not like that.
I want you to sign them
in front of me.
- Why don't you take some
time to think about it?
- No. It's. um...
It's over. Just... sign them.
Please.
It could have happened
to anyone.
Maybe.
But what if it happens again?
What then?
The kid got a couple stitches.
He's gonna be fine.
- You got him out of there.
- No. you did.
You were strong
out there today.
I was proud of you.
What are you gonna do?
A friend of mine
once suggested fishing.
Think I might take his advice.
- Fishing?
- Yeah.
Well. guys like us
don't go fishing.
[chuckles]
Where have I heard that before?
Senior...
Before you go.
I gotta know one thing.
What's your real number?
Twenty-two.
Twenty-two?
That's not bad...
It's not two hundred.
but it's not...
Twenty-two is the number
of people I lost. Jake.
Only number I kept track of.
Keeps the sea out of your mouth.
[dog barking]
[door opening]
- Hey.
- Hi.
You started painting again?
Yeah. Great light up there.
Yeah.
You know. um...
I want to apologize
for the phone calls. Helen.
I should have given you
your space.
And you felt showing up here
unannounced was the best way
to communicate that?
Hey.
- Please just... Now just...
- Ben.
I. I... I want you
to have it. along with...
Along with these.
I... I signed them.
Why now?
I had a...
I had a case a while back.
you know.
A couple was drowning.
By the time I got there.
the husband was...
dragging his wife under. just...
trying to stay afloat.
Pure survival instinct.
It took me. um...
It took me a long time
to understand that...
...that man was me.
- [exhales] Oh. man.
- [beeping]
Doggone it.
[turns off beeper]
Sorry.
Aren't you gonna
answer that?
I'm not a rescue swimmer
anymore. Helen.
[sniffling]
My baby.
[door opens and closes]
Lock it up!
We have a 75 foot fishing vessel
taking on water in high seas.
She's dead in the water
with four souls on board.
With its de-watering pumps
unable to keep up.
it's not a matter of if this
thing is going down. but when.
[man yelling indistinct]
[yelling indistinct]
- [alarm beeping]
- [radio chatter]
[Ben] There will come a time.
when you are going to have
to say no.
You'll be facing crews
from five to 20.
All saying. "save me. save me."
They're looking for a miracle.
At 24 years old.
you have to find a way
to be that miracle.
[pilot] Sounds good. We'll
plan our freefall deployment
to the water.
- You good with that. Jake?
- Copy that.
OK. if we have to put you in.
we're gonna get you in upswell.
and let the waves take you
down to the boat.
- You good with that?
- Roger.
We're only gonna have about
20 minutes on scene.
- So we gotta be quick.
- Copy that.
[pilot] All right.
I got the vessel in sight.
Two o'clock. about 50 meters.
[yelling]
Cabin door open and locked.
Pre-rescue checklist
for freefall deployment.
Whoa. whoa! Boat just took
a wave. sir. One appears
to have gone on the edge.
- He's hanging from
the cargo net.
- [screaming]
- Get our swimmer down there.
- [radio chatter]
[man] Deploy up top.
Prepare for freefall deployment
of the rescue swimmer.
[screaming]
Rescue checklist part two.
Swimmer's getting ready.
Rescue checklist complete.
Swimmer's coming out.
[pilot] Roger that.
Check swimmer.
Swimmer's at the door. sir.
Checking swimmer.
Swimmer ready?
God help you if you ain't. boy.
Swimmer's away.
Swimmer's OK. He's heading
toward the vessel.
He's cutting through
those waves pretty good.
That's it. He's approaching the
vessel... He's at the boat. sir.
Man. are we glad to see you!
[man on PA] Coast Guard
Cutter Alex Haley ten miles
southwest of Ashlock.
[pilot] Kodiak Ops. Rescue
6034. Fischer is on board.
but vessel is compromised.
Taking on lots of water.
May not hold much longer.
Stand by for further...
How many guys you got on here
and is anybody injured?
I've got four guys.
This guy's got a broken leg.
Skipper's down below.
He's trying to save the pumps.
All right. He's gonna go first.
All right!
[pilot] Kodiak Ops.
Rescue 6034.
Three on board with injuries.
one more down below.
What do you want me to do?
- [creaking]
- All right.
[grunting]
- Help me get him
around in here.
- Come on.
- Bring it on in. All right.
- [yelling]
Basket is on its way up.
[yelling]
- Drop in. Drop in.
- [groaning]
The captain's down below.
There's one other man on deck.
Help him out.
Get out of the way.
[pilot] I repeat.
the boat's going down fast.
Eight minutes to bingo.
All right. come on.
Get in the basket.
[pilot] I have the
ready-for-pickup signal.
Hold on.
[man] Swimmer one.
swimmer one. come in.
Rescue swimmer. 6034. Fischer.
come in. Fischer.
Swimmer one.
swimmer one. come in.
- [Jake] Swimmer one.
- Roger that. swimmer one.
Go ahead.
Swimmer one. I've got one down
below. I'm gonna go down there.
Swimmer one. be advised. We've
got seven minutes to bingo.
I'm going down.
- Captain.
- Yeah.
- Here.
[groaning]
Captain. I'm a rescue swimmer.
I'm here to help you out.
Is your leg jammed in here.
or is it just...?
[screams]
It's the whole leg.
I tried to free the clutch
and it got stuck. [groans]
This is swimmer one.
I got the captain down here
in the engine room. He's stuck.
- We're gonna be a little bit.
- [pilot] Swimmer one.
we're about out of time.
- That boat's listing bad and
we're two minutes to bingo.
- I ain't leaving without him.
Uh... Send somebody back
for us 'cause I'm staying
here with him.
[pilot] Negative. swimmer one.
We need you topside. ASAP.
- Swimmer one. 6034.
- [static]
Kodiak Ops. Kodiak Ops.
this is 6034.
Be advised.
we are RTB at this time.
We are leaving the rescue
swimmer on scene. I say again.
we are leaving our...
All right. What do we have
left in the shop?
- 08's all we've got left. sir.
But no crew.
- All right. Get her on line.
- Yes. sir.
- Lieutenant Krauss. suit up.
We're handling this.
I need a swimmer.
Don't worry.
No. no. They'll get him
[groaning]
Here we go.
Pull up.
- Ready to go home?
- Yeah. man.
[grunting]
Captain!
- We're cleared in. lieutenant?
- Aye. aye. captain.
Outstanding.
[grunting]
Rescue swimmer one.
this is 6008. Do you read?
Come in. rescue swimmer one.
6008. do you read me?
Come on. Jake. Be there.
[Jake grunting. banging]
[helicopter blades whirring]
Cabin door is open and locked.
All right. it's right there.
Right side. nobody on board.
All right. I see where I want.
Just get me down.
The right hand corner.
- Try to avoid the rigging.
- Swimmer requests aft.
right hand corner.
- Aft. right hand corner.
- OK. this is what
we're gonna do.
Do a rescue checklist part two
for a harness deployment
of the rescue swimmer.
[radio chatter]
- All right. we'll do
the hoist at 100 feet.
- Roger that.
Kodiak Ops. Kodiak Ops.
Rescue 6028.
[man] Rescue 6028.
Kodiak Ops. go ahead.
Swimmer's ready.
Load checking swimmer.
Load check complete.
Swimmer's going out the door.
Swimmer's out the door.
Swimmer's on his way down.
Coast Guard helo. do you copy?
Coast Guard helo. this is
rescue swimmer one. do you copy?
Port right 40.
Port right 30.
Watch your altitude.
[Hadley] Roger.
Hold. I have a fouled cable.
Hang it out flat.
Rescue helo. this is swimmer
number one!
I'm in the engine room and the
hull of the boat is filling up!
- [Krauss] Trying to
free the cable.
- Come on.
OK. cable free.
Cable free.
Attaboy.
Cable's free. They got a fray
right here. It's still good.
- I can use it. It's all we got.
- All right. good.
- Go back and left. captain.
- Back and left. roger that.
Jake!
Come on.
Come on!
Jake!
- Jake!
- Senior!
- Senior! I need help!
- Goldfish!
I checked all the locks on the
doors. I can't get it loose.
They're stuck.
I know. I see the problem.
It's filling up. Senior Chief!
Chief! Get me out of here!
- I'm almost submerged.
You gotta get the door open!
- Hold on. Jake.
[creaking]
[gasping]
- Senior. the captain's body.
- We gotta let it go. Come on.
Jake. he's gone!
Jake.
We got both swimmers coming
out. Both swimmers are in sight.
All right. I got 'em.
- [grunting]
- [yelling]
[straining]
Hook is going down. Let's go
port right 40. Halfway down.
I'm hooking into you. We're only
gonna get one shot at this.
I'm on.
I'm in!
I thought you were
going fishing.
What do you call this?
- [cable snaps]
- Whoa.
Cable's starting to burst.
The cable. Hold. hold. hold.
OK. hold right there.
We're bringing them up.
I gotta have that cable
up to the drop.
- What are you doing?
- [straining]
- [grunting]
- What are you doing?
- [unhooks latch]
- Don't even think about it.
It's not gonna hold us both.
What... Yes it will.
Don't! It'll hold!
[both grunting]
[Krauss] Senior fell.
Senior fell!
Jake's got him. Jake's got him.
I gotta get them up.
[groaning]
I won't let go!
I know.
[Jake] Senior!
Senior!
Lower me down!
He just fell. He just fell.
Randall fell.
- Lower me down!
- He's in the water.
Hit by a wave.
- Put me down!
- I can't.
You gotta lower me down. now!
- [cable breaks]
- Get me out of here!
- You gotta lower me down!
- I can't!
- I'll freefall!
- If I do. you don't come back.
I can't. I can't lose two.
Lost swimmer. Lost swimmer.
He saw the cable coming apart.
He just let go.
He was about 80/90 feet up. sir.
He didn't come up.
I don't see him.
Flash light. hover lights.
Not on the radio. sir.
No flare. strobe or anything.
He fell right into the debris.
Lost swimmer.
[Jake] The Coast Guard
conducted one of the largest
search and rescue missions
for a single man
in its history.
But the body of Senior Chief
Ben Randall was never found.
- I'm sorry. Helen.
- [sobs]
- [crying]
- There was nothing we could do.
[Jake] What makes a legend?
Is it what someone did
when they were alive...
[Hadley] Randall never was much
for this sort of thing.
...or how they're remembered
after they're gone?
Some people actually believe
Senior Chief made the swim
to the Aleutian Islands.
He's standing on a
distant beach somewhere
with a fishing pole
in his hand.
But I found my answer
a couple weeks later.
[shivering] Where is he?
Huh...? There's nobody else
out there. man.
No. he was there.
He was with me the whole time.
He said he would hold on
until help arrived.
He never let go.
[Jake] There's a legend
of a man who lives
beneath the sea.
He is a fisher of men.
A last hope for all those
who have been left behind.
He is known as The Guardian.
Ben Randall always said
life is about making choices.
In the end. by making his...
he helped me make mine.
What do you remember? What did
you smell. what did you see?
How did this make you...
...feel?
I'll be right back.
What are you doing here?
I lied to you.
I can't do casual.
[giggling]
[♪ Bryan Adams: Never Let Go]
♪ Can you lay your life down ♪
♪ So a stranger can live? ♪
♪ Can you take what you need ♪
♪ And take less
than you give? ♪
♪ Could you close every day ♪
♪ Without the glory and fame? ♪
♪ Could you hold
your head high ♪
♪ When no one
knows your name? ♪
♪ That's how legends are made ♪
♪ At least that's
what they say ♪
♪ We say goodbye ♪
♪ But never let go ♪
♪ We live. we die ♪
♪ 'Cause you can't
save every soul ♪
♪ Gotta take every chance to ♪
♪ Show that you're
the kind of man who ♪
♪ Will never look back.
never look down ♪
♪ And never let go ♪
♪ Can you lose everything ♪
♪ You ever had planned? ♪
♪ Can you sit down again ♪
♪ And play another hand? ♪
♪ Could you risk everything ♪
♪ For the chance
of being alone? ♪
♪ Under pressure.
find the grace ♪
♪ Or would you come undone? ♪
♪ That's how legends are made ♪
♪ At least that's
what they say ♪
♪ We say goodbye ♪
♪ But never let go ♪
♪ We live. we die ♪
♪ 'Cause you can't
save every soul ♪
♪ Gotta take every chance to ♪
♪ Show that you're
the kind of man who ♪
♪ Will never look back.
never look down ♪
♪ And never let go ♪
♪ Never let go ♪
♪ Gotta take every chance to ♪
♪ Show that you're
the kind of man who ♪
♪ Will never look back.
never look down ♪
♪ And never let go ♪
♪ We say goodbye ♪
♪ But never let go ♪
♪ We live. we die ♪
♪ But you can't
save every soul ♪
♪ Gotta take every chance to ♪
♪ Show that you're
the kind of man who ♪
♪ Will never look back.
never look down ♪
♪ Never let go ♪
♪ Will never look back.
and never look down ♪
♪ And never let go ♪
[♪ Marty James & Joseph
"Butch" Flythe:
Run Me In The Dirt
(Throwdown)]
♪ Oh-ah-oh-ah-ay ♪
♪ Run me. run me.
run me in the dirt. yeah ♪
♪ Oh-ah-oh-ah-ay ♪
♪ Run me. run me.
run me in the dirt. yeah ♪
♪ Oh-ah-oh-ah-ay ♪
♪ Yeah
You ready. man? ♪
♪ Run me. run me.
run me. make it hurt. yeah ♪
♪ It's on you ♪
♪ Now how do we decide
who lives and who dies ♪
♪ Heads or tails. set sails
and the goal's to survive ♪
♪ I'm always ready
I wear my heart on my sleeve ♪
♪ So that others may live so
that a stranger can breathe ♪
♪ Now. I live by the sea
and my life is a storm ♪
♪ You comin' with me
and we'll get to the shore ♪
♪ This is hardcore my brothers
gotta live for this ♪
♪ I got love for ooh-rah
Class 5506. come on ♪
♪ Oh-ah-oh-ah-ay ♪
♪ I got one life. one shot
so what's it gonna be. now ♪
♪ Fly me. fly me.
fly me out to sea. yeah ♪
♪ I can't think twice tonight.
man. I'm ready to throw down ♪
♪ Oh-ah-oh-ah-ay ♪
♪ I got one life. one shot
So what's it gonna be. now ♪
♪ People in the water
waiting for me. yeah ♪
♪ I can't think twice tonight.
man. I'm ready to throw down ♪
♪ Oh-ah-oh-ah-ay ♪
♪ Run me. run me.
run me in the dirt. yeah ♪
♪ Oh-ah-oh-ah-ay ♪
♪ Kick me. kick me.
kick me out the door. yeah ♪
♪ Oh-ah-oh-ah-ay ♪
♪ Save fifty people
and come back for more. yeah ♪
♪ Oh-ah-oh-ah-ay ♪
♪ Run me. run me.
run me in the dirt. yeah ♪
♪ Oh-ah-oh-ah-ay ♪
♪ Run me. run me.
run me. make it hurt. yeah ♪
Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today